## SOPON UDOMPHON



092-906-1183



mr.sopon.udo@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sopon-udomphon

#### SUMMARY

Experienced and detail-oriented chemist specialized in the synthesis of nano-scale and polymeric materials, with developing their features for various applications including biomedical, anti-corrosion, and sensor technologies. Familiar in ISO:IEC 17025:2017 standards, gained through work at the Laboratory for Biocompatibility Testing of Medical Devices



#### **EXPERIENCE**

- Operate various packaging machinery, including filling, labeling, and sealing machines, while adhering to company SOPs.
- Ensure effective communication with foreign supervisors, and other departments to resolve packaging-related issues and maintain quality control.
- Proficient in organizational skills and adept at collaborating with authors, clients, and crossfunctional teams within editorial and production departments.
- Effective communication with scholars and academic stakeholders from oversea involved in the journal publication process.
- Researching and developing the pioneering new materials and product in anti-corrosion and environmental detection features.
- Leading the marketing team in a small startup business including comprehensive market research and patent analysis
- Researching and developing the Ziegler-Natta catalyst in laboratory scale reactor.
- Planing to analyst and interpret the developed catalyst including comprehensive the crystallographic structure (XRD) and chemical characteristic (NMR and ICP).
- Researching and developing the nano-scale polymer materials (micelles and liposomes) including comprehensive the polymer synthesis and functionalization (based on organic chemistry), characterisations (physical and chemical properties), and application (drug delivery system).
- Up-scaling the polymer synthesizing into a reactor pilot.
- Starting and developing system of the Laboratory for Biocompatibility Testing of Medical Devices to become ISO:IEC 17025:2017 standards

#### **Production Staff**

Carton Finishing
Australia
April 2023 - Dec 2023

#### **Assistant Editor**

MDPI (Thailand) Co., Ltd, Thailand

July 2022 - Feb 2023

#### **Project Researcher**

Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology (VISTEC), Thailand

Oct 2021 - Jun 2022

#### Researcher (contract)

SCG-MUSC Innovation Research Center, Thailand

Jun 2018 - July 2021

#### Research Assistant

Mahidol University (BioNEDD Lab), Thailand

Aug 2015 - Jun 2021

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters Degree in Science**

Polymer Science and Technology

Mahidol University May 2017 - Sep 2021

#### **Bachelors Degree in Science**

Applied Chemistry (Polymer Science and Technology)

Mae Fah Luang University Jun 2011 - Jun 2015

# PUBLICATION/ CONFERENCES / AWARD

W Assawapanumat, **S Udomphon**, N Nasongkla, et al. 99mTc/SPIO-loaded polymeric micelles as MRI and SPECT imaging, cancertargeted nanoprobe for liver cancer detection. *Journal of Drug Delivery Science and Technology*, Vol.79 (2023).

International Polymer Conference of Thailand (PCT-11)

### Best Poster Award (Runner up)

July 1-2, 2021

Pure and Applied Chemistry International Conference 2019 (PACCON 2019) Feb 7-8, 2019

The 26th Annual Meeting of the Thai Society for Biotechnology and International Conference

**Best Poster Award** 

Nov 26-29, 2014

#### **SKILLS**

- Project management
- Data Analysis

- Problem solving
- Marketing Research
- Programming (Python/R/SQL)
- Patents Analysis